  <model name="mainmodelparam" title="Main model parameters" layout="flat">
  <desc>
Please enter the name of each model running in the experiment using the button "add Models", 
double clicking on the new row created and filling the part "no label" under "Model names". 
The name must be validated using the button "Enter" of the keyboard. 
The "load" button is useless for the OASIS3-MCT application.
The maximum fortran unit is optional, but if it is specified for one model, it 
must be specified for all the models. []
The blue (?), located at the right bottom of this window, gives more information on each data to fill up.
When processing this window, it will be necessary to save the xml file.
  </desc>
  </model>
  <model name="modelparam" title="Model parameters" layout="flat">
    <multiple name="models" title="Models" custom_label="Model names">
         <xor name="maxunits" title="Maximum fortran units" default="units_off">
           <model name="units_off" title="No fortran units">
           </model>
           <model name="units_on" title="Max fortran units">
             <param name="nunit" title="Max Fortran units (integer)" type="integer" />
           </model>
         </xor>
    </multiple>
    <info name="model_names_list" title="List of the models" type="liststring" visibility="hidden"/>
    <docu> 
[section=Model names]

In this part the user must enter the names of the models running in the experiment, 
which must correspond to the name announced by each model when calling the routine oasis_init_comp
(see section 2.2.1 of the User Guide).

Then the user may indicate the maximum Fortran unit number used by the models.

More information can be found in the User Guide section 3.2 under the keyword $NBMODEL.
<docuold>
In all cases, OASIS3-MCT library assumes, during the
initialization phase, that units 1025 and 1026 are free and temporarily uses these units to
read the configuration file and to write corresponding log messages to file nout.000000. After the
initialization phase, OASIS3-MCT will still suppose that units above 1024 are free, unless maximum
unit numbers are indicated in the configuration file.
</docuold>
    </docu>
  </model>

