 <model name="fldproper" title="Coupling fields properties" layout="flat">
  <desc> 
Please enter the coupling period, the name of the restart files and the status for 
the different coupling fields, selecting the different rows available.
If you have many fields, it is possible to propagate the properties of one field 
to the others using the button "copy". 
The "load" button is useless for the OASIS3-MCT application.[]
A blue (?), located at the right bottom of this window, gives more information on the data to fill up, specially on the
INPUT and OUTPUT field properties.
  </desc>
 </model>

 <model name="cplrststatus" title="Coupling fields properties" layout="flat">
    <multiple name="crs" title="Coupling period, restarts, status" require="field_names_list" custom_label="Fields" size="1.5;1.5">
         <param name="cpl" title="Coupling or IO period in s (integer)" type="integer" />
         <param name="restart" title="Restart file (NetCDF)" type="string" />
         <choice name="status" title="Status" type="string" default="exported">
               <option value="exported" title="EXPORTED"/>
               <option value="expout" title="EXPOUT"/>
               <option value="input" title="INPUT"/>
               <option value="output" title="OUTPUT"/>
         </choice>
    </multiple>
    <docu> 
[section=NetCDF Restart files]
The name of the coupling restart file for the field is mandatory even if no coupling restart file is effectively used. []

More information on the restart files can be found in the User Guide section 2.10 and section 5.2.

[section=Status of the fields]
[item=EXPORTED:] The field is exchanged between component models and transformed by OASIS3-MC
[item=EXPOUT:] The field is exchanged, transformed and also written to two debug NetCDF files (after LOCTRANS and BLASOLD before 
remapping and after all transformations after remapping).
[item=INPUT:] The field is read in from the input file by the target model.
[item=OUTPUT:] The field is written out to an output debug NetCDF file by the source model. 

More information is available in section 3.3 of the User Guide.

<docuold>
[section=NetCDF Restart files]
The name of the coupling restart file for the field is mandatory even if no coupling restart file is effectively used. []

At the beginning of a coupled run, some coupling fields may have to be initially read from their coupling restart 
file on their source grid. When needed, these files are also automatically updated by the last active oasis_put 
call of the run. Warning: the date is not written or read to/from the restart file; therefore, the 
user has to make sure that the appropriate coupling restart file is present in the working directory. The coupling 
restart files must follow the NetCDF format. []

Coupling fields coming from different models cannot be in the same coupling restart files, 
but for each model, there can be an arbitrary number of fields written in one coupling restart file. The only exception 
is when a coupling field sent by a source component model is associated with more than one target field and model; 
in that case, if coupling restart files are required, it is mandatory to specify different files for the different fields. []

In the coupling restart files, the fields must be provided on the source grid in single or double precision REAL arrays and, 
as the grid data files, must be dimensioned (nx, ny), where nx and ny are the grid first and second dimension. The shape and 
orientation of each restart field (and of the corresponding coupling fields exchanged during the simulation) must be coherent 
with the shape of its grid data arrays. []

The coupling restart files are also used automatically by OASIS3-MCT to allow partial LOCTRANS time transformation 
to be saved at the end of a run for exact restart at the start of the next run. For that reason, coupling restart 
filenames are now required for all namcouple transformations that use LOCTRANS (with non INSTANT values).

[section=Status of the fields]
The field may be : []
- EXPORTED: exchanged between component models and transformed by OASIS3-MCT []
- EXPOUT: exchanged, transformed and also written to two debug NetCDF files, one before the sending action in 
the source model below the oasis_put call (after local transformations LOCTRANS and BLASOLD if present), and one 
after the receiving action in the target model below the oasis_get call (after all transformations). EXPOUT should 
be used when debugging the coupled model only. The name of the debug NetCDF file (one per field) is automatically 
defined based on the field and component model names. []
- INPUT: read in from the input file by the target model below the oasis_get call at appropriate times corresponding 
to the input period indicated by the user in the namcouple. []
- OUTPUT: written out to an output debug NetCDF file by the source model below the oasis_put call, after local
transformations LOCTRANS and BLASOLD, at appropriate times corresponding to the output period indicated by 
the user in the configuration file. 
</docuold>
    </docu>
</model>







