<model name="intro" title="OASIS3-MCT coupler" layout="flat">
    <desc> 
        [image=header_final.gif]
        OASIS3-MCT coupler Graphical User Interface
    </desc>
    <docu>


The OASIS coupler, is a software allowing synchronized exchanges of coupling information between numerical codes 
representing different components of the climate system. Current OASIS developers are CERFACS (Toulouse, France) 
and Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique (Paris, France). []

OASIS3-MCT, the new version of the OASIS coupler interfaced with the Model Coupling Toolkit (MCT) from the Argonne National 
Laboratory, offers today a fully parallel implementation of coupling field regridding and exchange. Low-intrusiveness, portability 
and flexibility are OASIS3-MCT key design concepts as for all previous OASIS versions. An important difference with respect 
to previous OASIS3.3 is that there is no separate coupler executable: OASIS3-MCT is a coupling library that 
needs to be linked to the component models, to interpolate and exchange the coupling 
fields between these components. []


OASIS3-MCT supports coupling of general two-dimensional fields. Unstructured grids and 3D grids are also supported 
using a one dimension representation of the two or three dimensional structures. Thanks to MCT, all transformations, including 
regridding, are executed in parallel on the set of source or target component processes and all coupling exchanges are now 
executed in parallel directly between the components via Message Passing Interface (MPI). OASIS3-MCT also supports file I/O 
using NetCDF, allowing an easy switch between the coupled and forced modes. In the current version, the implementation of this 
functionality is however non parallel with the reading/writing of the fields performed only by the master process of the model. []


In spite of the significant changes in underlying implementation, usage of OASIS3-MCT in the component code has largely 
remained unchanged with respect to OASIS3.3. To communicate with another model, or to perform I/O actions, a component 
model needs to include a few specific calls to the OASIS3-MCT coupling library, using the same API as in OASIS3.3. The 
configuration file (namcouple) is also largely unchanged relative to OASIS3, although few options are either not used 
or not supported. []


The scalability tests done with OASIS3-MCT at high number of cores and the fact that it supports unstructured grids allow 
us to conclude that this coupler offers today a fully parallel and efficient coupling solution answering the short and mid 
term needs of the European climate modelling community. []


More information can be found on the OASIS web site: https://oasis.enes.org
    </docu>
</model>

<model name="generaldesc" title="Generalities on the GUI" layout="flat">
    <desc> Generalities on the Graphical User Interface : []
[section=Generalities] []
This GUI was developed to create the configuration file (namcouple) of OASIS3-MCT.
The configuration file contains all user defined information necessary to configure a
particular coupled run. The first part of the file is devoted to general parameters
such as the runtime or the level of debugging.
The second part gathers specific information
on each coupling (or I/O) field, e.g. their coupling period, the list of transformations
or interpolations to be performed by OASIS3-MCT.
All these informations will be defined step by step through this interface to finally be
written in the configuration file by the GUI (processing the last tab "Config"). []
   </desc>
</model>

<model name="guidesc" title="Decription of the GUI" layout="flat">
    <desc> Short description of the Graphical User Interface : []

[section=Usage]
All windows defined by the different tabs below the OASIS logo
must be filled up, from the left to the right. When all data of a window is 
defined, the window must be validated by clicking on button "Process"
at the bottom right. If the information provided in the window is correct, the corresponding
orange (?) bullet becomes green in the tab. An orange (?) bullet in the tab means that 
no information was stored yet in the window or that the information was not yet validated,
a red (X) bullet in the tab means that there is an error in the window, 
and, as already explained, a green (v) bullet in the tab means that
the data entered in the window is correct.
If there is a problem in a tab (red (X) bullet), an error message giving more
information is printed in the bottom window of the GUI.
If you want to close the GUI (File/Quit) before the proper creation of the configuration file in the last tab, it
is possible to save the information entered in an xml file. You can reload your xml file
using the (File/Load as new) menu at the left top of the GUI (do not use the (File/Load as part) menu).
Some documentation about the data to be provided by the user in the different windows is available by clicking on the 
different blue bullets (?) entitled "Learn more".[]
The first parameters to enter, in the tab "Gen", will be the simulation length, the debugging
level and the timing information printed by OASIS3-MCT.
If grouped fields have to be defined (i.e. fields using the same configuration settings sent in a single communication) 
the "Enable grouped field" must be activated.
In this case a new tab "Group" will appear to define the different groups.
Then the grid characteristics of the coupling fields in
the "Grids" window, and the different names of the coupling fields (before and after transformations), grouped or not,
in the tab "Fld Name".[] 
Finally all characteristics and transformations associated to each coupling field (or grouped fields) have to be defined step 
by step in the following windows. 
If the first four tabs "Main", "Gen", “Grids” and "Fld Names" are not filled up and processed before the others, 
it will not be possible to enter information about the coupling fields in the following windows.[] 
At some point when filling the GUI or when closing it, the data of the GUI must be saved in an xml file which name
is chosen by the user.
A summary of the transformations chosen for the coupling fields will be printed when processing
the tab "Sum".
The  final configuration text file will be created and printed in the last window "Config" when processing it, only if
WHEN ALL THE TABS ARE VALIDATED  (in a directory named after the name of the xml file, see the README file). [] 

[section=Documentation]
Some documentation is available by clicking on the different blue bullets (?).
It is also possible to get all the OASIS3-MCT documentation in an html format by using the functionality
(File/General help) located at the left top of the GUI.
    </desc>
</model>

