<model name="scriptransfo" title="SCRIP Interpolation" layout="flat">
     <desc>
Please enter if the remapping is done with the SCRIP library, for the different coupling fields,
selecting the different rows available.
The "load" button is useless for the OASIS3-MCT application.[]
A blue (?), located at the right bottom of this window, gives more information on the data to fill up.
     </desc>
</model>
<model name="transfinterp" title="Remapping" layout="flat">
    <multiple name="interp" title="Scripr options" require="field_names_list" custom_label="Fields">
        <xor name="scrip" title="SCRIPR" default="scrip_off">
            <model name="scrip_off" title="NO SCRIP">
            </model>
            <model name="scrip_on" title="SCRIP">
                <xor name="scriprinterp" title="Type of interpolation" default="bilinear">
                    <model name="distwgt" title="DISTWGT">
                        <choice name="cgrs_dist" title="Type of source grid" type="string">
                            <option value="lr_dist" title="LR"/>
                            <option value="d_dist" title="D"/>
                            <option value="u_dist" title="U"/>
                        </choice>
                        <choice name="rest_dist" title="Search restriction type" type="string">
                            <option value="latlon_dist" title="LATLON"/>
                            <option value="latitude_dist" title="LATITUDE"/>
                        </choice>
                        <param name="nbin_dist" title="Nb of restriction bins (integer)" type="integer"/>
                        <param name="nv_dist" title="Nb of neighbours used (integer)" type="integer"/>
                        <desc> Distance weighted nearest-neighbour interpolation (N neighbours).
                        </desc>
                    </model>
                    <model name="gauswgt" title="GAUSWGT">
                        <choice name="cgrs_gaus" title="Type of source grid" type="string">
                            <option value="lr_gaus" title="LR"/>
                            <option value="d_gaus" title="D"/>
                            <option value="u_gaus" title="U"/>
                        </choice>
                        <choice name="rest_gaus" title="Search restriction type" type="string">
                            <option value="latlon_gaus" title="LATLON"/>
                            <option value="latitude_gaus" title="LATITUDE"/>
                        </choice>
                        <param name="nbin_gaus" title="Nb of restriction bins (integer)" type="integer"/>
                        <param name="nv_gaus" title="Nb of neighbours used (integer)" type="integer" />
                        <param name="var_gaus" title="Weight given to the neighbour used" type="double"/>
                        <desc> N nearest-neighbour interpolation weighted by their distance and a gaussian function.
                               For D and U grids, the restriction bin must be one.
                        </desc>
                    </model>
                    <model name="bilinear" title="BILINEAR">
                        <choice name="cgrs_bili" title="Type of source grid" type="string" >
                            <option value="lr_bili" title="LR"/>
                            <option value="d_bili" title="D"/>
                        </choice>
                        <choice name="rest_bili" title="Search restriction type" type="string" >
                            <option value="latlon_bili" title="LATLON"/>
                            <option value="latitude_bili" title="LATITUDE"/>
                        </choice>
                        <param name="nbin_bili" title="Nb of restriction bins (integer)" type="integer"/>
	                <desc> Bilinear interpolation. Only LATITUDE is possible with D source grid
                        </desc>
                    </model>
                    <model name="bicubic" title="BICUBIC">
                        <choice name="cgrs_bicu" title="Type of source grid" type="string">
                            <option value="lr_bicu" title="LR"/>
                            <option value="d_bicu" title="D"/>
                        </choice>
                        <choice name="rest_bicu" title="Search restriction type" type="string">
                            <option value="latlon_bicu" title="LATLON"/>
                            <option value="latitude_bicu" title="LATITUDE"/>
                        </choice>
                        <param name="nbin_bicu" title="Nb of restriction bins (integer)" type="integer"/>
	                <desc> Bicubic interpolation. Only LATITUDE is possible with D source grid
                        </desc>
                    </model>
                    <model name="conserv_interp" title="CONSERV">
                        <choice name="cgrs_conserv" title="Type of source grid" type="string" >
                            <option value="lr_conserv" title="LR"/>
                            <option value="d_conserv" title="D"/>
                            <option value="u_conserv" title="U"/>
                        </choice>
                        <choice name="rest_conserv" title="Search restriction type" type="string">
                            <option value="latlon_conserv" title="LATLON"/>
                            <option value="latitude_conserv" title="LATITUDE"/>
                        </choice>
                        <param name="nbin_conserv" title="Nb of restriction bins (integer)" type="integer" />
                        <choice name="norm_conserv" title="Normalization option" type="string" >
                            <option value="fracnnei_conserv" title="FRACNNEI"/>
                            <option value="fracarea_conserv" title="FRACAREA"/>
                            <option value="destarea_conserv" title="DESTAREA"/>
                        </choice>
                        <choice name="order_conserv" title="Order of the interpolation" type="string" >
                            <option value="first_conserv" title="FIRST"/>
                            <option value="second_conserv" title="SECOND"/>
                        </choice>
	                <desc> Conservative interpolation. 
                        </desc>
                    </model>
                </xor> 
            </model>
        </xor>
    </multiple>
    <docu> 
[section=SCRIP library]
The SCRIP1.4 library gather the interpolation techniques offered by Los Alamos National Laboratory (Jones 1999). 
The SCRIP library routines are in oasis3-mct/lib/scrip/src. See the documentation in oasis3-mct/doc/SCRIPusers.pdf for more 
details on the interpolation algorithms. 


When the SCRIP library performs a remapping, it first checks if the file containing the corresponding remapping weights 
and addresses exists; if it exists, it reads them from the file; if not, it calculates them and store them in a file. 
The file is created in the working directory and is called rmp_srcg_to_ tgtg_INTTYPE_NORMAOPT.nc, where srcg and tgtg 
are the acronyms of respetively the source and the target grids, INTTYPE is the interpolation type, i.e. DISTWGT, GAUSWGT, 
BILINEAR (not BILINEA as in OASIS3.3) or CONSERV -see below, and NORMAOPT is the normalization option, i.e. DESTAREA, 
FRACAREA or FRACNNEI for CONSERV only -see below). One has to take care that the remapping file will have the same 
name even if other details, like the grid masks, are changed. When reusing a remapping file, one has to be sure that 
it was generated in exactly the same conditions than the ones it is used for. []

More details on the types interpolations that are available can be found in the User Guide section 4.3.

<docuold>
The following types of interpolations are available: []

[section=DISTWGT] 
Performs a distance weighted nearest-neighbour interpolation (N neighbours). All types of grids are supported. []
- Masked target grid points: the zero value is associated to masked target grid points. []
- Non-masked target grid points having some of the N source nearest neighbours masked: a 
nearest neighbour algorithm using the remaining non masked source nearest neighbours is applied. []
- Non-masked target grid points having all of the N source nearest neighbours masked: by default, the 
nearest non-masked source neighbour is used (logical ll_nnei hard-coded to .true. in 
oasis3-mct/lib/scrip/src/remap_distwgt.F; same default behaviour as OASIS3.3). []

[section=GAUSWGT] 
Performs a N nearest-neighbour interpolation weighted by their distance and a gaussian function. All grid types are supported. []
- Masked target grid points: the zero value is associated to masked target grid points. []
- Non-masked target grid points having some of the N source nearest neighbours masked: a nearest neighbour 
algorithm using the remaining non masked source nearest neighbours is applied. []
- Non-masked target grid points having all of the N source nearest neighbours masked: by default, the nearest 
non-masked source neighbour is used (logical ll_nnei hard-coded to .true. in oasis3-mct/lib/scrip/src/remap_gauswgt.F); 
this is NOT the same default behaviour as OASIS3.3; to have the same default behaviour as in OASIS3.3, put ll_nnei=.false.. []

[section=BILINEAR and BICUBIC] 
BILINEAR performs an interpolation based on a local bilinear approximation (see details in chapter 4 of SCRIP 1.4 documentation SCRIPusers.pdf). 
Logically-Rectangular (LR) and Reduced (D) source grid types are supported. []

BICUBIC performs an interpolation based on a local bicubic approximation for Logically-Rectangular (LR) grids, 
and on a 16-point stencil for Gaussian Reduced (D) grids. 
Note that for Logically-Rectangular grids, 4 weights for each of the 4 enclosing source neighbours are required corresponding 
to the field value at the point, the gradient of the field with respect to i, the gradient of the field with respect to j, 
and the cross gradient with respect to i and j in that order. OASIS3-MCT will calculate the remapping weights and addresses 
(if they are not already provided) but will not, at run time, calculate the two gradients and the cross-gradient of the 
source field (as was the case with OASIS3.3). These 3 extra fields need to be calculated by the source code and transfered 
as extra arguments of the oasis_put. []

- Masked target grid points: the zero value is associated to masked target grid points. []
- Non-masked target grid points having some of the source points normally used in the bilinear or bicubic 
interpolation masked: a N nearest neighbour algorithm using the remaining non masked source points is applied. []
- Non-masked target grid points having all bilinear or bicubic neighbours masked: by default, the nearest 
non-masked source neighbour is used (ll_nnei hard-coded to .true. in oasis3-mct/lib/scrip/src/remap_bilinear.f, 
remap_bicubic.f and remap_bicubic_reduced.f); this is not the same default behaviour as OASIS3.3; to have the same 
default behaviour as in OASIS3.3, put ll_nnei=.false. in the appropriate routine. []  

[section=CONSERV] 
Performs 1st or 2nd order conservative remapping, which means that the weight of a source cell is proportional to 
area intersected by the target cell (plus some other terms proportional to the gradient of the field in the longitudinal 
and latitudinal directions for the second order). []

Note that the grid corners have to given by the user in the grid data file grids.nc or by the code itself in the 
initialisation phase by calling routine oasis_write_corner ; OASIS3-MCT will not attempt to automatically calculate 
them as OASIS3.3. []

The following types of normalisations are available: []
- FRACAREA: The sum of the non-masked source cell intersected areas is used to NORMalise 
each target cell field value: the flux is not locally conserved, but the flux value itself is reasonable. []
- DESTAREA: The total target cell area is used to NORMalise each target cell field value even if it only 
partly intersects non-masked source grid cells: local flux conservation is ensured, but unreasonable flux 
values may result. []
- FRACNNEI: as FRACAREA, except that at least the source nearest unmasked neighbour is used for unmasked 
target cells that intersect only masked source cells. Note that a zero value will be assigned to a target 
cell that does not intersect any source cells (masked or unmasked), even with FRACNNEI option. []

For CONSERV/SECOND, 3 weigths are needed; OASIS3-MCT will calculate these weights and corresponding addresses 
(if they are not already provided) but will not, at run time, calculate the two extra terms to which the 
second and third weights should be applied; these terms, respectively the gradient of the field with respect 
to the longitude and the gradient of the field with respect to the latitude,
need to be calculated by the source code and transfered as extra arguments of the oasis_put. []

Note that CONSERV/SECOND is not positive definite and has not been fully validated yet. []

[section=Precautions related to the use of the SCRIPR/CONSERV remapping]
- For the 1st order conservative remapping: the weight of a source cell is proportional to area of the 
source cell intersected by target cell. Using the divergence theorem, the SCRIP library evaluates this  
area with the line integral along the cell borders enclosing the area. As the real shape of the borders  
is not known (only the location of the 4 corners of each cell is known), the library assumes that the  
borders are linear in latitude and longitude between two corners. This assumption becomes less valid 
closer to the pole and for latitudes above the north_thresh or below the south_thresh values 
(see oasis3-mct/lib/scrip/src/remap_conserv.F, the library evaluates the intersection between two border 
segments using a Lambert equivalent azimuthal projection. Problems were observed in some cases for 
the grid cell located around this north_thresh or south_thresh latitude. []
- Another limitation of the SCRIP 1st order conservative remapping algorithm is that is also supposes, 
for line integral calculation, that sin(latitude) is linear in longitude on the cell borders which 
again is in general not valid close to the pole. []
- For a proper consevative remapping, the corners of a cell have to coincide with the corners of 
its neighbour cell, with no ``holes'' between the cells. []
- If two cells of one same grid overlay, at least the one with the greater numerical index must be 
masked for a proper conservative remapping. For example, if the grid cells with i=1 overlays the 
grid cells with i=imax, the latter must be masked. If this is not the case given the mask defined 
in masks.nc, OASIS3-MCT must be compiled with the CPP key TREAT_OVERLAY which will ensure that these 
rules are respected. This CPP key was introduced in OASIS3.3. []
- A target grid cell intersecting no source cell (either masked or non masked) at all i.e. falling 
in a ``hole'' of the source grid will in all cases get a zero value. []
- If a target grid cell intersects only masked source cells, it will still get a zero value unless 
the FRACNNEI normalisation option is used, in which case it will get the nearest non masked neighbour 
value. Note that the option of having the value 1.0E+20 assigned to these target grid cell intersecting 
only masked source cells (for easier identification) is not yet availble in OASIS3-MCT.
</docuold>
    </docu>
</model>
