 <model name="timetransfo" title="Time transfos" layout="flat">
   <desc>
Please enter the time tranformations, if any, for the different coupling fields,
selecting the different rows available.
The "load" button is useless for the OASIS3-MCT application.[]
A blue (?), located at the right bottom of this window, gives more information on the data to fill up.
   </desc>
</model> 
 <model name="transftime" title="Time transformations" layout="flat">
 <multiple name="time" title="Time options" require="field_names_list" custom_label="Fields">
	 <xor name="loctrans" title="LOCTRANS" layout="flat" default="loctrans_off">
	   <model name="loctrans_off" title="NO LOCTRANS">
           </model>
	   <model name="loctrans_on" title="LOCTRANS">
	     <choice name="loctransdef" title="Type of time transformation" type="string" default="average">
               <option value="average" title="AVERAGE"/>
	       <option value="accumul" title="ACCUMUL"/>
               <option value="tmin" title="T_MIN"/>
               <option value="tmax" title="T_MAX"/>
	     </choice>
           </model>
         </xor>
</multiple>
    <docu> 

[section=Time transformations definitions]

[item=INSTANT (default, corresponds to NO LOCTRANS option):] No time transformation, the instantaneous field is transferred []
[item=ACCUMUL:] The field accumulated over the previous coupling period is exchanged (the accumulation 
is simply done over the arrays field_array provided as third argument to the oasis_put calls, 
not weighted by the time interval between these calls) []
[item=AVERAGE:] The field averaged over the previous coupling period is transferred (the average is 
simply done over the arrays field_array provided as third argument to the oasis_put calls, not 
weighted by the time interval between these calls)  []
[item=T_MIN:] The minimum value of the field for each source grid point over the previous 
coupling period is transferred []
[item=T_MAX:] The maximum value of the field for each source grid point over the previous 
coupling period is transferred []

More details can be found in the User Guide section 4.1.

<docuold>
With OASIS3-MCT, time transformations are supported more generally with use of the coupling restart file.
The coupling restart file allows the partial time transformation to be saved at the end of a run for exact
restart at the start of the next run. For that reason, coupling restart filenames are now required for all
namcouple entries that use LOCTRANS. This is the reason an optional restart file is
now provided on the OUTPUT namcouple input line. 
</docuold>
    </docu>
</model>








