 <model name="conservtransfo" title="Conservation transformation" layout="flat">
     <desc>
Please define the redistribution, if any, for the different coupling fields
selecting the different rows available.
The "load" button is useless for the OASIS3-MCT application.[]
A blue (?), located at the right bottom of this window, gives more information on the data to fill up.
     </desc>
 </model>
 <model name="transfconserv" title="Conservation option" layout="flat">
    <multiple name="conservation" title="Conserv option" require="field_names_list" custom_label="Fields">
         <xor name="conservopt" title="Conserv or not" default="conserv_off">
	   <model name="conserv_off" title="NO CONSERV">
	   </model>
	   <model name="conserv_on" title="CONSERV">
	     <choice name="conservstrategy" title="How to do the redistribution" type="string" default="global">
               <option value="global" title="GLOBAL"/>
               <option value="glbpos" title="GLBPOS"/>
               <option value="basbal" title="BASBAL"/>
               <option value="baspos" title="BASPOS"/>
	     </choice>
	     <choice name="conservalgo" title="Algorithm" type="string" default="bfb_conserv_on">
	       <option value="bfb_conserv_on" title="Bit-for-bit reproductibility"/>
               <option value="opt_conserv_on" title="Optimized"/>
	     </choice>
           </model>
	 </xor>
       </multiple>
    <docu> 
[section=CONSERV option]
CONSERV ensures a global modification of the coupling field. This analysis requires the source and target 
grid mesh areas to be transfered to the coupler with oasis_write_area and oasis_write_mask. For a correct 
CONSERV operation, overlapping grid cells on the source grid or on the target grid must be masked. [] 

[section=Types of redistribution]
The following types of options are available: []
- GLOBAL, the field is integrated on both source and target grids, without considering values of masked points, 
and the residual (target - source) is uniformly distributed on the target grid; this option ensures 
global conservation of the field []
- GLBPOS, the same operation is performed except that the residual is distributed proportionally to the value 
of the original field; this option ensures the global conservation of the field and does not change 
the sign of the field []
- BASBAL, the operation is analogous to GLOBAL except that the non masked surface of the source and the 
target grids are taken into account in the calculation of the residual; this option does not ensure global 
conservation of the field but ensures that the energy received is proportional to the non masked surface 
of the target grid []
- BASPOS, the non masked surface of the source and the target grids are taken into account and the residual 
is distributed proportionally to the value of the original field; therefore, this option does not ensure 
global conservation of the field but ensures that the energy received is proportional to the non masked 
surface of the target grid and it does not change the sign of the field. []

More information is available in the User Guide section 4.4.

<docuold>
[section=Algorithm]
The algorithm used to perform the redistribution can be "Bit-for-bit reproductibility" (bfb) 
or "Optimized" (opt). The bfb option enforces a bit-for-bit transformation regardless of 
the grid decomposition or process count. The opt option carries out the conservation using an optimal algorithm 
using less memory and a faster approach. Option bfb is the default setting.
</docuold>
    </docu>
</model>








